Guide to the Northwest Horticultural Council Records 1953-1977
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Northwest Horticultural Council Records
1953-1977
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Cage 516
Northwest Horticultural Council
17 Linear feet of shelf space 17 Boxes
Correspondence and records of the Northwest Horticultural Council, relating to the opening of the Northwest fruit industry to new markets, materials on railroad rates, Interstate Commerce Commission rules and rulings, council bulletins, testimonies before Congress, fruit statistics, and personal records of Ernest Falk.
The Northwest Horticultural Council was organized in 1947 by horticulturalists in Oregon and Washington in order to coordinate the efforts of the Perishable Traffic Bureau and the Oregon-Washington Horticultural Export Council as well as local organizations in Medford and Hood River, Oregon, and Yakima and Wenatchee, Washington. The initial purpose was to present a unified position in the face of federal government decisions and regulations effecting the Northwest fruit industry. Other stated objectives of the Council included the promoting of domestic and foreign trade, dealing with the pesticide issue, resolving problems common to the fruit producers and shippers, and generally advancing the interests of Northwest horticulturalists. From its headquarters in Yakima, the Council currently represents approximately 7500 growers and 200 shippers.
The collection consists of correspondence and records of the Northwest Horticultural Council, spanning the period 1953 through 1977, and relating to the opening of the Northwest fruit industry to new markets, materials on railroad rates, Interstate Commerce Commission rules and rulings, council bulletins, testimonies before Congress, fruit statistics, and personal records of Ernest Falk.
Series one, Correspondence, covers the years 1961 through 1977, and makes up about half the collection. It deals with a wide variety of matters concerning the Council: United States legislative aid for Northwest fruit marketing abroad, government regulations regarding pesticides, labor relations, labor organization and regulations, migrant labor and ideas for improving the fruit products of Washington and Oregon. Some of the letters concern the efforts of grower organizations to coordinate lobbying and promotional activities.
Series two, Exports, includes records of Northwest fruit industry executive contacts in foreign countries ranging from members of the European Common Market through the Middle East to the Far East and Latin America. These documents record the efforts of American industry representatives to open new markets for Northwest products such as cherries or apples, and negotiations with United States and foreign officials concerning trade and tariff regulations in various countries.
Series three, transportation, records Council negotiations and lobbying with the federal government on railroad rates and regulation and also a number of court cases concerning railroad rates. Interstate Commerce Commission rules and rulings fill several documents. Furthermore, Council meetings with other West Coast Shippers on sea transport and international shipping rates constitute a major element in these letters.
Series Four combines a variety of miscellaneous letters stretching from 1953 to 1977. They include extensive correspondence of the Northwest Horticultural Council Board of Trustees, Council Bulletins from 1970 to 1975, Council testimonies before Congress between 1953 and 1967, fruit statistics from 1967 to 1970, a survey of the European apple and pear production and marketing, and personal records of Ernest Falk.
The records of the Northwest Horticultural Council are arranged so as to interfile the records transferred to the Libraries in three distinct occasions. A portion of these records was partially un-foldered and re-arranged at some point in time. As these files were not in office arrangement, the Libraries' staff used a simple chronological arrangement to give these papers some order. Other folders were still identifiable according to the office filing scheme and were interfiled with the papers received on separate occasions. The first half of the Correspondence series is arranged chronologically. The remaining correspondence and other three series, Export, Transportation, and Miscellaneous Documents, are arranged alphabetically and topically.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Records of the Northwest Horticultural Council were transferred to the Washington State University Libraries in August, 1980 (MS80-34), December, 1981 (MS81-51), and in September, 1982 (MS82-36) by Ernest Falk, Manager.
Northwest Horticultural Council Records, 1951-1976 (Cage 383)
Western Washington Horticultural Association Records, 1972-1977 (Cage 358)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Falk, Ernest -- Records and correspondence
Northwest Horticultural Council -- Records and correspondence; International Apple Association; United Fresh Fruit and Vegetable Association
Fruit trade -- Records and correspondence; Agriculture -- Northwest, Pacific -- Societies, etc. -- Records and correspondence; Fruit -- Transportation
Agriculture; Transportation; Washington (State); Oregon
- Series 1: Correspondence
  - Subseries 1.1: Chronological Files, 1961-1975
    - July 1-September 26, 1961, 180 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - October 3, 1961-February 28, 1962, 200 items. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - March 1, 1962-June 19, 1962, 125 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - July 9, 1962-September 14, 1962, 150 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - October 2, 1962-February 27, 1963, 200 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - March 1, 1963-June 10, 1963, 150 items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - July 1, 1963-September 30, 1963, 200 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - October 1, 1963-December 30, 1963, 125 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - January 2, 1964-June 30, 1964, 250 items. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - July 2, 1964-December 31, 1964, 350 items. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - January 4, 1965-June 30, 1965, 250 items. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - July 3, 1965-June 30, 1965, 275 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - January 4, 1966-June 30, 1966, 400 items. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - June 27, 1966-December 29, 1966, 400 items. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - January 3, 1967-June 30, 1967, 500 items. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - July 31, 1967-June 28, 1968, 500 items. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - July 1, 1968-December 31, 1968, 375 items. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - January 2, 1969-June 30, 1969, 350 items. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - July 1, 1969-December 31, 1969, 300 items. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - January 2, 1970-June 26, 1970, 450 items. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - June 25, 1970-December 30, 1970, 300 items. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - January 5, 1971-June 30, 1971, 250 items. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - July 1, 1971-December 30, 1971, 300 items. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - January 3, 1972-June 30, 1972, 250 items. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - July 3, 1972-June 30, 1972, 300 items. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - January 2, 1973-June 29, 1973, 400 items. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - July 2,1973-December 31, 1973, 275 items. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - January 3, 1974-June 28, 1974, 325 items. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - July 1, 1974-December 3, 1974, 350 items. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - January 2, 1975-June 27, 1975, 400 items. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Subseries 1.2: Topical Files
    - Subseries 1.2.1: 1971-1975
      - A General Correspondence, 1974-1975; 13 items. (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Apple Production, 1974; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Apple Prices and Costs, 1974-1975; 11 items. (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - B General Correspondence, 1974-1975; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - California Grape and Fruit Tree League, 1974-1975; 30 items. (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Cash Disbursements, 1974-1975; 14 items. (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - Chamber of Commerce, 1974-1975; 11 items. (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Cherries, summer
        - 1974-1975, 58 items. (Box 4, Folder 38)
        - 1971-1972, 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Conference on Food Productivity, 1974; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Congressional Correspondence, 1974-1975; 18 items. (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Consumer Food Act of 1975, 8 items. (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - Council of Fruit and Vegetable Executves, 1974-1975; 16 items. (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - D General Correspondence, 1974-1975; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Domestic International Sales Corporation, 1972-1973; 12 items. (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - E General Correspondence, 1974-1975; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - Energy and Fuel Crisis, 1973-1974; 40 items. (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - Environmental Protection Agency
        - 1974-1975, 38 items. (Box 4, Folder 48)
        - Pesticides, 1973-1974; 30 items. (Box 4, Folder 49)
        - Pesticides, 1974; 11 items. (Box 4, Folder 50)
        - Pesticides, 1974-1975; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 51)
        - Use Permits, 1974; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 52)
        - Health and Safety Standards, 1974; 50 items. (Box 4, Folder 53)
        - Heath and Safety Standards, 1974; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 54)
        - Heath and Safety Standards, 1974-1975; 18 items. (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Equal Employment Opportunity, November 25, 1974; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - F General Correspondence, 1974-1975; 7 items. (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - Farm Labor Legislation, 1974-1975; 7 items. (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - Farm Labor Legislation, Washington State, 1974; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 59)
      - Fair Labor Standards Act, 1974; 10 items. (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - Farm Labor Unionization, 1973-1974; 24 items. (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - Farm Labor Unionization, 1974-1975; 23 items. (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - Farm Labor Unionization, Contracts, 1971-1972; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 63)
      - Federal Environmental Pesticide Control Act of 1973, 1971-1975; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 64)
      - Federal Trade Commission, 1974-1975; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 65)
      - Food and Drug Act
        - 1974-1975, 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 66)
        - Foreign, 1974; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 67)
        - Pesticides, 1974-1975; 56 items. (Box 4, Folder 68)
        - Zero Tolerance, 1973; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 69)
      - G General Correspondence, 1975; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 70)
      - Goodfruit Grower, 1975; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 71)
      - Grades and Standards: Apples and Pears, 1974-1975; 8 items. (Box 4, Folder 72)
      - Grades and Standards, Other States, 1974-1975; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 73)
      - Grapes, 1974; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 74)
      - H General Correspondence, 1975; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 75)
      - Hood River Traffic Association Bulletins, 1975; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 76)
      - I General Correspondence, 1974; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 77)
      - International Apple Institute, 1974-1975; 19 items. (Box 4, Folder 78)
      - International Apple Institute, Special Letter, 1974-1975; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 79)
      - K General Correspondence, 1974; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 80)
      - M General Correspondence, 1975; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 81)
      - Marketing Agreement, Federal, 1974; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 82)
      - Mexican Nationals--Migratory Workers, 1974-1975; 20 items. (Box 4, Folder 83)
      - National Council of Agricultural Employers, 1974; 11 items. (Box 4, Folder 84)
      - National Council of Agricultural Employers, 1975; 62 items. (Box 4, Folder 85)
      - National Council of Agricultural Employers, 1974-1975; 17 items. (Box 4, Folder 86)
      - National Labor Relations Act, 1975; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 87)
      - National Legislation, 1974-1975; 15 items. (Box 4, Folder 88)
      - O General Correspondence, 1975; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 89)
      - Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, 1974-1975; 17 items. (Box 4, Folder 90)
      - Occupational Health Standards--Washington, 1974-1975; 7 items. (Box 4, Folder 91)
      - Occupational Health Standards, 1974; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 92)
      - Occupational Health Standards, Federal Agriculture, 1974-1975; 10 items. (Box 4, Folder 93)
      - Oregon Horticultural Society, 1974; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 94)
      - Oregon Horticultural Society, 1974; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 95)
      - Oregon, Washington, California Pear Bureau, 1974-1975; 34 items. (Box 4, Folder 96)
      - P General Correspondence, 1974-1975; 6 items. (Box 4, Folder 97)
      - Perishable Agricultural Commodities Act, 1975; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 98)
      - Pacific Coast Deciduous Fruit Council, 1974-1975; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 99)
      - Pacific Coast Deciduous Fruit Council, 1975; 6 items. (Box 4, Folder 100)
      - Packaging and Labeling Restrictions, 1974; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 101)
      - R General Correspondence, 1974-1975; 6 items. (Box 4, Folder 102)
      - Research Commission, 1974-1975; 7 items. (Box 4, Folder 103)
      - S General Correspondence, 1974-1975; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 104)
      - School Lunches, 1975; 50 items. (Box 4, Folder 105)
      - T General Correspondence, 1975; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 106)
      - Tree Fruits, 1974; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 107)
      - United Fresh Fruit and Vegetable Association, 1974-1975; 50 items. (Box 4, Folder 108)
      - United States Chamber of Commerce, 1974-1975; 34 items. (Box 5, Folder 109)
      - United State Dept. of Agriculture, 1974-1975; 31 items. (Box 5, Folder 110)
      - United States - Appropriations, 1974-1975; 2 items. (Box 5, Folder 111)
      - United States Depts. of State and Labor, 1975; 3 items. (Box 5, Folder 112)
      - W General Correspondence, 1974-1975; 3 items. (Box 5, Folder 113)
      - Washington Agricultural Producers Council, 1972-1973; 11 items. (Box 5, Folder 114)
      - Washington State Apple Commission
        - 1974-1975, 10 items. (Box 5, Folder 115)
        - Merchant Act, 1973-1974; 26 items. (Box 5, Folder 116)
        - 1975, 16 items. (Box 5, Folder 117)
        - 1974-1975, 50 items. (Box 5, Folder 118)
      - Washington State-Department of Agriculture, 1974-1975; 6 items. (Box 5, Folder 119)
      - Washington State Dept. of Commerce, 1974-1975; 4 items. (Box 5, Folder 120)
      - Washington State Dept. of Ecology, 1974; 2 items. (Box 5, Folder 121)
      - Washington State Dept. of Labor and Industries, 1974-1975; 8 items. (Box 5, Folder 122)
      - Washington State Dept. of Employment Security, 1974-1975; 12 items. (Box 5, Folder 123)
      - Washington State Horticultural Assn, 1973-1974; 3 items. (Box 5, Folder 124)
      - Washington State Horticultural Ass'n, 1974-1975; 31 items. (Box 5, Folder 125)
      - Washington State Legislation, 1974-1975; 10 items. (Box 5, Folder 126)
      - Washington State Legislation, Tax Commission, 1974; 4 items. (Box 5, Folder 127)
      - Washington Women For The Survival of Agriculture, 1972-1975; 19 items. (Box 5, Folder 128)
      - Wenatchee Valley Traffic Association Bulletins
        - 1971-1972, 75 items. (Box 5, Folder 129)
        - 1972-1973, 100 items. (Box 5, Folder 130)
        - 1973-1974, 6 items. (Box 5, Folder 131)
        - 1974, 6 items. (Box 5, Folder 132)
        - 1974-1975, 100 items. (Box 5, Folder 133)
      - Western International Trade Group and Washington State, 1974-1975; 17 items. (Box 5, Folder 134)
      - Winter Pear Control Correspondence
        - 1974, 15 items. (Box 5, Folder 135)
        - 1971-1972, 14 items. (Box 5, Folder 136)
        - 1972-1973, 16 items. (Box 5, Folder 137)
        - 1973-1974, 18 items. (Box 5, Folder 138)
        - 1974-1975, 23 items. (Box 5, Folder 139)
      - World Agricultural Production and Trade, 1975; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 140)
      - Yakima Valley Growers and Shippers Association Bulletins
        - 1971-1972, 175 items. (Box 5, Folder 141)
        - 1972-1973, 175 items. (Box 5, Folder 142)
        - 1974, 3 items. (Box 5, Folder 143)
        - 1973-1974, 165 items. (Box 5, Folder 144)
        - 1974-1975, 135 items. (Box 5, Folder 145)
        - 1974-1975, 20 items. (Box 5, Folder 146)
    - Subseries 1.2.2: 1975-1976
      - Apple Crop and Condition Report, 1975-1976; 3 items. (Box 6, Folder 147)
      - Apple Production, 1975-1976; 9 items. (Box 6, Folder 148)
      - Assessments, 1975-1976; 18 items. (Box 6, Folder 149)
      - Association of Washington Industries, 1975-1976; 36 items. (Box 6, Folder 150)
      - Bank Deposits, 1975-1975; 16 items. (Box 6, Folder 151)
      - Bills Paid, 1975-1976; 147 items. (Box 6, Folder 152)
      - Board of Trustees, 1975-1976; 123 items. (Box 6, Folder 153)
      - California Grape and Tree Fruit League, 1975-1976; 57 items. (Box 6, Folder 154)
      - State Regulations, 1975-1976; 17 items. (Box 6, Folder 155)
      - Cash Disbursements, 1975-1976; 20 items. (Box 6, Folder 156)
      - Chamber of Commerce, 1975-1976; 24 items. (Box 6, Folder 157)
      - Cherries, 1975-1976; 38 items. (Box 6, Folder 158)
      - Cherries, NW Negotiation with Japan, 1975-1976; 47 items. (Box 6, Folder 159)
      - Cherries, United States-Japan Negotions, 1976; 54 items. (Box 6, Folder 160)
      - China Council For The Promotion of International Trade, 1975; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 161)
      - Conference on Food Productivity, Costs and Prices, 1975-1976; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 162)
      - Congressional Correspondence, 1975-1976; 52 items. (Box 6, Folder 163)
      - Consumer Food Act of 1975, 1975-1976; 3 items. (Box 6, Folder 164)
      - Council of Fruit and Vegetable Association Executives, 1975-1976; 19 items. (Box 6, Folder 165)
      - Energy and Fuel Crisis, 1975-1976; 26 items. (Box 6, Folder 166)
      - Environmental Protection Agency, 1975-1976; 38 items. (Box 6, Folder 167)
      - Environmental Protection Agency, 1975; 43 items. (Box 6, Folder 168)
      - EPA - Experimental Use Permits, 1975-1976; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 169)
      - EPA - Health and Safety Standards, 1975-1976; 3 items. (Box 6, Folder 170)
      - EPA - Pesticides
        - 1975, 17 items. (Box 6, Folder 171)
        - 1975-1976, 17 items. (Box 6, Folder 172)
      - Fair Labor Standards Act, 1975-1976; 16 items. (Box 6, Folder 173)
      - Farm Labor, 1975-1976; 78 items. (Box 6, Folder 174)
      - Farm Labor Contractor Registration Act, 55 items. (Box 6, Folder 175)
      - Farm Labor Legislation, Washington State, 1975-1976; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 177)
      - Farm Labor Unionization, 1975-1976; 17 items. (Box 6, Folder 178)
      - Farm Labor Unionization, Yakima Valley, 1975-1976; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 179)
      - Federal Trade Commission, 1975-1976; 14 items. (Box 6, Folder 180)
      - Food and Drug Act, 1975-1976; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 181)
      - Foreign Regulations, 1975; 4 items. (Box 6, Folder 182)
      - Miscellaneous, 1975-1976; 7 items. (Box 6, Folder 183)
      - Food and Drug Regulations, 1975-1976; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 184)
      - Foreign Investment, 1976; 17 items. (Box 6, Folder 185)
      - Grades and Standards, Apple and Pear, 1975-1976; 6 items. (Box 6, Folder 186)
      - 1975-1976, 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 187)
      - Hop Growers of America, 1976; 7 items. (Box 6, Folder 188)
      - International Apple Institute, 1975-1976; 23 items. (Box 6, Folder 189)
      - League of Women Voters of Yakima County, 1976; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 190)
      - Marketing Agreement, Federal, 1975-1976; 19 items. (Box 6, Folder 191)
      - Mexican Nationals, Migratory Workers, 1975-1976; 27 items. (Box 6, Folder 192)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1975-1976; 16 items. (Box 6, Folder 193)
      - National Council of Agricultural Employers
        - 1975-1976, 145 items. (Box 6, Folder 194)
        - 1976, 184 items. (Box 6, Folder 195-196)
      - National Labor Relations Act, 1975-1976; 5 items. (Box 6, Folder 197)
      - National Legislation, 1975-1976; 79 items. (Box 6, Folder 198)
      - Employment of Aliens, 1975-1976; 10 items. (Box 6, Folder 199)
      - Occupational Health Standards, 1975-1976; 9 items. (Box 6, Folder 200)
      - Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, 1975-1976; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 201)
      - Oregon Horticultural Society, 1975-1976; 5 items. (Box 6, Folder 202)
      - Oregon-Washington-California Pear Bureau, 1975-1976; 28 items. (Box 6, Folder 203)
      - Pacific Coast Deciduous Fruit Council, 1975-1976; 20 items. (Box 6, Folder 204)
      - Perishable Agricultural Commodities Act, 1975-1976; 36 items. (Box 6, Folder 205)
      - Prices and Costs, 1975-1976; 3 items. (Box 6, Folder 206)
      - Research Commission, 1975-1976; 8 items. (Box 6, Folder 207)
      - Research and Public Relations, 1976; 21 items. (Box 6, Folder 208)
      - School Lunch, 1975-1976; 123 items. (Box 6, Folder 209)
      - Spray, Organic, 1975-1976; 114 items. (Box 6, Folder 210)
      - Strict Liability, 1975-1976; 78 items. (Box 6, Folder 211)
      - Traffic Association Trust Fund, 1975-1976; 11 items. (Box 6, Folder 212)
      - Unemployment Compensation For Farm Workers, 1975-1976; 4 items. (Box 6, Folder 213)
      - United Fresh Fruit and Vegetable Association, 1975-1976; 200 items. (Box 7, Folder 214-216)
      - United States Chamber of Commerce, 1975-1976; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 217)
      - United States Departments of State and Labor, 1975-1976; 7 items. (Box 7, Folder 218)
      - United States Dept. of Agriculture, Appropriations, 1975-1976; 4 items. (Box 7, Folder 219)
      - United States Fruits and Vegetables, 1974-1975; 25 items. (Box 7, Folder 220-221)
      - Washington Pesticide Control Act, 1975-1976; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 222)
      - Washington State Apple Commission, 1975-1976; 13 items. (Box 7, Folder 223)
      - Washington State Commission Merchants Act, 1975-1976; 11 items. (Box 7, Folder 224)
      - Washington State Department of Agriculture, 1975-1976; 12 items. (Box 7, Folder 225)
      - Washington State Department of Commerce, 1975-1976; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 226)
      - USDA (misfiled), Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1975-1976; 27 items. (Box 7, Folder 227)
      - Washington State Department of Health, 1975-1976; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 228)
      - Washington State Department of Labor and Industries, 1975-1976; 17 items. (Box 7, Folder 229)
      - Washington State Department of Employment Security, 1975-1976; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 230)
      - Washington State Department of Employment Security, 1975-1976; 6 items. (Box 7, Folder 231)
      - Washington State Horticultural Association, 1975-1976; 23 items. (Box 7, Folder 232)
      - Washington State Legislation, 1975-1976; 12 items. (Box 7, Folder 233)
      - Washington State Tax Commission, 1975-1976; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 234)
      - Washington Women For The Survival of Agriculture, 1975-1976; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 235)
      - Washington Workmen's Compensation, 1975-1976; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 236)
      - Wenatchee Valley Growers-Shippers Association, 1975-1976; 20 items. (Box 7, Folder 237)
      - Wenatchee Valley Traffic Association, 1975-1976; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 238)
      - Western International Trade Group, 1975-1976; 5 items. (Box 7, Folder 239)
      - Winter Pear Control Correspondence, 1975-1976; 7 items. (Box 7, Folder 240)
      - Witholding Tax, 1975-1976; 7 items. (Box 7, Folder 241)
      - Yakima Valley College, 1975-1976; 10 items. (Box 7, Folder 242)
    - Subseries 1.2.3: 1976-1977
      - Apple Crop and Condition Report, 1976-1977; 5 items. (Box 7, Folder 243)
      - Apple Production, 1976-1977; 5 items. (Box 7, Folder 244)
      - Assessments - NHC, 1976-1977; 19 items. (Box 7, Folder 245)
      - Bank Deposits - NHC, 1976-1977; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 246)
      - Bills Paid - NHC, 1976-1977; 37 items. (Box 7, Folder 247)